天啊
Oh, my God!
不敢相信
I can't believe
我的小老弟结婚了
my little brother's married!
难以置信
No way!
你们私订终身  怎么不告诉我一声
Why didn't you tell me you were eloping?
因为我们事先也没想到
Cause it just sort of happened,
那天我们在法院
you know, we were at the court house,
吃午饭  等等  你们干嘛去法院
we're having lunch... Wait, wait, Why were you at the courthouse?
就是去那儿吃午饭啊
We were having lunch.
突然之间
And then all of a sudden,
我们灵光一现
we were like... hey, you know,
既然都来法院吃午饭了
we're here, we're having lunch.
不如顺便把婚结了吧
Let's get married! Right?
我还不知道自己有个弟弟
A year ago, I didn't know I had a brother.
结果现在又多了个弟妹
Now I have a sister!
真是太棒了
Oh, it's so great.
行了
Okay.
够了
停  别再亲了
Stop it! Don't!
我得送你们新婚礼物才行
So, what...I'll get you a gift now.
你们需要什么吗
Is there anything you need?
我们订婚后
We've been trying to get pregnant
我就一直想怀上宝宝
pretty much ever since we got engaged,
心想越早生越好
to get a jump on things.
毕竟已经青春不再了嘛
You know, no one's getting any younger.
可问题是  我总也怀不上
Because the thing is, we're not able to, you know, conceive.
我们把该试的都试遍了
And we've tried everything,
也咨询过了很多医生
We've seen a bunch of doctors.
对  他们说我们若想生小孩
Yeah, and they say that our only chance to have a baby...
唯有把我的精子和她的卵子
is that if they take my sperm, her egg,
放进培养皿里头
and put it together in a dish...
再放进另一个女人的子宫里
and then put it into another girl.
不知道你愿不愿意让我们向你借腹生子
So, we were wondering if you could be that girl that we could put it into.
这礼物选得还真有水平
That's a really nice gift.
我还以为你们会想要个酱料皿呢
I was thinking of...like a gravy boat.
大伙快看过来  看过来
Hey! You guys! Check it out! Check it out!
猜我找了份什么工作
Guess what job I just got.
不知道  不过你该把唐纳·川普
I don't know, but Donald Trump wants his
蓝色夹克"黄"回去了
blue blazer black.
什么
What?
把蓝色外套"还"回去  是"还"回去
Blue blazer back. He wants it back.
可你刚才说的是"黄"
But you said "black".
为什么让他把蓝外套"黄"回去
Why would he want his blue blazer black?
你知道我的意思
Well, you know what I meant.
不  是你玩笑没开好  闪着舌头了
No. You messed it up.
你笨死了
You're stupid.
乔伊  你找着什么工作了
So, what job did you get, Joe?
在博物馆当导览员  罗斯帮我争取到的
Oh, uh...tour guide at the museum. Yeah. Ross got it for me.
你还能在博物馆当导览员
How can you be a tour guide?
不是得恐龙专家才行吗
Don't you have to be a dinosaur expert?
不尽然  他们会把资料都给你
No, not really. They give you all the information.
就跟背剧本没什么两样
It's like memorizing a script.
大家请看  左边是暴龙雷克斯
Yeah. And on your left you have a tyrannosaurus Rex,
它是侏罗纪时代的肉食性恐龙
a carnivore from the Jurassic Period.
不赖嘛  乔伊
Very nice, Joey.
其实暴龙是生活在白垩纪的
Yeah, actually, Joey, it's the Cretaceous Period.
但我就是为了显摆我会说侏罗纪这个词
Yeah. But I can pronounce Jurassic.
你们猜怎么着  弗兰克和爱丽丝结婚了
Hey, guess what.Frank Jr. and Alice got married!
天啊
Oh, my God!
而且他们就要生小孩了
And they're having a baby!
而且他们还想借我的腹生子
And...and they want meto grow it for them in my uterus!
-天啊  -你是认真的吗
- My God! - Are you serious?
是啊  你真的要和自己的亲弟弟上床吗
Yeah! You're thinking of having sex with your brother?
你真恶心  才不是
Ew! And, oh, no!
我只是当个代孕母亲
It's that they just want me to be the surrogate.
卵子还是她的卵子  精子还是他的精子
It's her egg and his sperm.
我只是个烤箱  烤出的点心也是他们的
And I'm just the oven. It's only their bun.
那你答应了没
What did you tell them?
他们说要先让我考虑一下  但有啥好考虑的
Well, they said that I had to think about it first,but what is there to think of?
这是我能向他们俩送出的最重的厚礼了
I'm gonna be giving someone the greatest gift you can possibly give.
你帮他们怀孩子  还要加送索尼PS游戏机吗
You'll carry their child and get them a Sony PlayStation?
你这样做对他们来说的确是雪中送炭
Honey, this really is an incredible thing to do for them.
但是你也得考虑到一些事
But there are things to think about.
对啊  这可是要怀孕啊
Yeah, I mean, you'd be pregnant.
我知道啊
I know.
菲比  你可知道怀孕意味着
Pheebs, you're talking about
你的身体将经受许多摧残与折磨
You'll put your body through an awful lot.
你会晨吐  要经历分娩的痛苦
I mean, morning sickness, labor.
结果到最后自己什么也没捞着
And it's all for somebody else.
你到底想说什么
Yeah. What's your point?
该说的我都说了啊
Well, the stuff I just mentioned.
这种事我一定做不到
I don't know if I could ever do that.
我一直憧憬着  自己第一次怀孕
You know, I always figured the first time I had a baby,
一定怀的是我心爱的人的孩子
it'd be with someone I love.
而孩子出生之后
And that baby was, you know...
一定要留在我身边
a keeper.
字我当时要用牛仔布做家具时
You know, you guys were a lot more supportive
你们都还比较支持
when I wanted to make denim furniture.
菲比  如果你心意已决
Oh, Pheebs, listen, if you decide to do this,
我们一定无条件支持你
we'll be supportive like crazy.
我们只是想让你仔细考虑清楚
Yeah. We just want you to think it through.
或许你应该和生过小孩的人
Yeah, and maybe you could talk to somebody
讨论一下  比如你妈妈
who's had a baby. Like your mom.
我妈又没生过小孩  不过我的生母生过孩子
My mom never gave birth. Oh! But my birth mom did!
我喜欢你的小翘臀  可以让我带去上班吗
I love this tushy! Can I take it to work with me?
没问题  反正也不是我的  是买裤子附赠的
Yeah, sure. It's not mine anyway. It came with the pants.
我嫉妒死了
I am so jealous.
你们俩真的好投入
You guys are just right there.
是啊
Yes.
投入什么
Right where?
恋爱初期  除了滚床单就是打情骂俏
The beginning, where, you know, it's all sex and talking...
然后再滚床单  再打情骂俏
and sex and talking and...
至少打情骂俏的部分很不错
Yeah, you got to love the talking.
那滚床单呢
And the sex?
好吧  我承认我们还没上过床
We haven't had sex.
有什么好大惊小怪的  这样才特别啊
Okay, but what's the big deal? You know, this is special.
我希望先慢慢培养我们的爱情
I want our love to grow
然后再进入下一个阶段
before moving to the next level.
钱德勒  你这想法太迷人了
Oh, Chandler, that is so nice.
真是迷人的...
That is really nice...
谎言
lying!
-不可能是这个原因  -为什么
- No way is that the reason. - Why?
别以为人人都像你这么不成熟
Just because you're not mature enough
无法理解那种境界
to understand something like that?
不  他说的对  我撒了个弥天大谎
No. He's right. I'm totally lying.
那真相是什么?
Then what is it?
因为凯茵前任男友是乔伊
Kathy's last boyfriend was Joey.
你担心自己技不如人吗
And you're afraid you won't be able to fill his shoes?
不  我只是担心自己床上功夫没他好
No. I'm afraid I won't make love as well as him.
我本不想把话挑明的
I was going for the metaphor.
是啊  所以我干脆替你把话说明白了
I was saying the actual words.
没关系的  就算乔伊交过一卡车女友
What's the big deal? So Joey's had a lot of girlfriends.
也不表示他的床技一流啊
It doesn't mean he's great in bed.
我和他的卧房仅一墙之隔
We share a wall.
若非他真的很强  就是他女友很喜欢跟他互动
So either he's great in bed,or she just liked to agree with him a lot.
亲爱的  你们的情况不一样
Sweetie, with you, it's gonna be different.
有爱做基础  一定会更性福
The sex will be great because you guys are in love.
-是吗  -是啊
- Yeah?  - Yeah!
放手一试吧  钱德勒
Just go for it, Chandler.
-试试看就知道了  -没错  加油
- Yeah, you should. -Come on, really.
好吧  我去跟女友滚床单
All right. I'll sleep with my girlfriend.
但我纯粹是为了成全你们
But I'm just doing it for you guys.
我们现在看到的这头乳齿象生活在株罗纪半晚期
Okay, now, the mastodon is from the semi-late Jurassic Period.
乳齿象不应该是上新世的吗
Isn't the mastodon from the Pliocene Epoch?
这里是博物馆  不许喧哗
This is a museum. No talking.
这里展出的是
Right down here we have...
一只大脚
a large foot.
这位是罗斯·盖勒
And over here we have Ross Geller.
大家和罗斯打个招呼吧
Everyone wave "hi" to Ross.
罗斯是馆内最重要的科学家之一
Ross is one of our most important scientists.
看他工作得多卖力
Look at him hard at work.
好  我们继续参观吧
Okay, moving right along.
走吧
Come on.
门没锁  请进
It's open. Come in.
-抱歉迟到了  -没关系
- I'm sorry I'm late. - Oh. That's okay.
我正好有时间给我的乳头上釉
It give me time to finish glazing my nipples.
为了见客  还真是大费周章啊
Wow, you really go all out when you're expecting company.
你想多了  我说的是陶器
No. I was working on my pottery.
我不知道你会捏泥人啊
Oh! I didn't know that you did pot.
对  而且大多是裸体人像
Oh yeah. Mostly nudes.
这结合我的两种爱好  陶艺与色情
It combines my two passions: Pottery and erotica.
-就叫做"陶情"吧  -行啊
- Erottery! - Okay!
谢谢你来看我
Thanks for coming out to see me.
我只是觉得生孩子这件事
I just, I just thought it'd be a very good idea
还是当面聊比较好
to talk about this baby stuff in person, you know.
菲比  我觉得这样不妥
I really don't think it's a good idea, Phoebe.
为什么
Why not?
因为你得把你生下来的孩子送给别人
Well, because you'd be giving up a baby.
我不知道...
And I really don't...
不知道要怎么说...
I don't know if anything I said...
你才会懂送走孩子会有多么痛苦
that could make you understand the pain of giving up a baby.
不  我能体会那种痛苦
No, no, I understand the pain.
千万  不要伤害小狗
Don't...don't hurt the puppy!
不  不是  这小狗是你的了
No, no. The puppy is yours.
-送我了  -对  但只给你3天
- I get a puppy? - Yeah, I mean, but for only three days.
为什么
Why?
我知道我早已无权
Well, you know, I realize I don't have any right
搬出为人父母的权威来向你说教
to start getting all parenty on you everything now.
菲比  请你别看小狗了
Phoebe, would you please look at me
看着我  我要说很重要的事
and not the puppy. It's very important.
我下面要说的话  句句发自肺腑
I mean, I know what I'm talking about.
我曾将两个亲生孩子送给别人
I gave up two babies.
真希望当时能有遗弃过孩子的前辈来告诉我
I only wish I had someone who'd given up babies that told me...
送走自己的小孩会有多痛苦
how terrible it is to give up babies.
我只是觉得送走孩子后
I just think that it'd be something
在你的有生之年  每天都会饱尝悔恨
you'd regret every single day for the rest of your life.
你送走这条小狗的痛苦
So however hard it is for you to give up this puppy...
远不及送走孩子的痛苦的百万分之一
it'd be a million times harder to give up a child.
你能不能坐对面  我帮朋友罗斯留了位置
Could you sit there? I'm saving this seat for my friend Ross.
你是说盖勒博士
You mean Dr. Geller?
博士  我还不知道他有这绰号
Doctor? I didn't know he had a nickname.
他才不会坐这里呢
Oh, he won't sit here.
穿白色工作服的人都会坐在那里
Only people in white coats sit there.
而穿蓝色外套的只能坐这里
Only people in blue blazers sit here.
-为什么这样  -一向如此
- How come? - That's just the way it is.
岂有此理
That's crazy.
或许在不分蓝白的完美世界里
Maybe it's crazy in a perfect world:
你的确可以抱怨"岂有此理"
a world without lab coats and blazers.
但你不是活在完美世界  这里是博物馆
But you not in a perfect world.You in a museum now.
看到那戴眼镜的科学家没
See that scientist with glasses?
想当年我们念小学  总在一起玩  但现在呢
He and I used to play together in grade school, but now....
彼得  嘿  彼得
Peter! Hey, Peter!
我是朗妲  我们是同届的啊
It's me! Rhonda, from P.S. 129?
亏我把布丁分你吃过
I shared my pudding with you, man!
我还把点心棒送给你吃过呢
I gave you my Snack Pack!
看到没  他假装统统没听到
See? He pretend he don't even hear me!
我想大家都在假装没听到
I think everyone's pretending they don't hear you.
我是不懂什么蓝白制服之别
Anyway, I don't know about you
还有什么分桌吃饭的规矩...
and your jackets and your separate tables...
不过罗斯是我的死党
but Ross is one of my best friend.
如果我帮他留了位置
And if I save him a seat,
我向你打包票  他一定会坐
I'm telling you, he will sit in it.
罗斯  来这儿坐  我帮你留了位置
Ross! Over here, man. I saved you a seat!
我坐这里就好  待会儿再去找你聊
I'm cool over here. I'll catch up with you later.
这个位置有人了
This is saved.
她是礼品店的
Gift shop.
我要向你道歉
I'm really, really sorry about
为今天发生在餐厅的事情
what happened in the cafeteria today.
这没什么  你该怎样就怎样吧
It's no big deal. You know, you do what you got to do.
别这样  不是只有我一人这样做
No, hey, it's not just me.
科学家和导览员从来是不坐在一起的
I mean, the scientists and the tour guides never sit together.
随你的便
Whatever.
乔伊  每家企业都是这样的
It's like that everywhere, Joey.
莫妮卡  帮我说说话啊
Okay, Mon, back me up here.
在你工作的地方  侍者和侍者一起吃饭
Where you work, the waiters eat with the waiters, right?
厨师和厨师吃饭  对吧
And the chefs eat with the other chefs, right?
我是自己躲在巷子里吃  因为大家都恨我
I eat by myself in the alley, because everybody hates me.
罗斯  你听我说
Look, Ross.
这没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
你穿白色工作服  我穿蓝色外套
You wear a white coat. I wear a blue blazer.
若这表示上班期间不能当朋友  我也接受
If that means we can't be friends at work, so be it.
我能理解
I understand, you know?
我演舞台剧  你坐观众席
When I'm in a play and you're in the audience,
我也不会跟你说话  是吧
I don't talk to you.
所以没事了
So it's, you know, it's cool.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
我们当观众的时候
When we're in the audience,
他是不跟我们说话
he doesn't talk to us,
但却会向我们招手
but he does wave.
菲比为什么要唱歌给卡尔·马登听
Why's Phoebe singing to Karl Malden?
我好像又该去遛狗了
You know what? I think it's time for puppy to go out again.
走  我们去阳台
Come on, let's go to the balcony.
什么  去大街上  走吧  我们遛大街去
What? The street. Come on, let's go to the street.
对了  在我回来之前  你们都别去阳台
Oh, listen, don't go on the balcony until after I get back.
你做了没
So did you do it?
有 我们上床了
Yes, yes, we had the sex.
很糟糕吗
It was bad?
好是好  但是她附和我的程度
It was fine, you know, but she didn't agree with me
不像附和乔伊那样强烈
as strongly as with Joey.
感觉像是  "我知道你有多大能耐了
She was like, "L see your point.
既然如此  就这样吧"
I'm all right with it."
这才第一次嘛
It was the first time, you know.
第一次的互动总是比较生疏
There's not always a lot of agreement the first time.
对  女人需要慢慢来
Yeah. Not for girls, anyway.
不像男生  一碰就互动了
Guys agree like that.
你们得帮帮我
Look, you have to help me, okay?
我是说
I mean...
我知道怎样在床上取悦女人
I know what to do with a woman.
我知道怎样一步步渐入佳境
You know, I know where everything goes.
我的那些经历都很美好
It's always nice.
但我想知道  怎样才能从"美好"进阶到
I need to know...what makes it go from nice to:
"天呐  听听那动静  真像是谋杀"
"My God! Somebody's killing her in there!"
好吧  我来向你展示一下
All right, I'm gonna show you something
很多男人都不知道的东西
a lot of guys don't know.
瑞秋  把便笺本递给我一下
Rach, give me that pad, please.
好吧
All right.
马上就好
Now.
你不用真的画出个女哇  身材真惹火
You don't have to draw an actual Whoa, she's hot!
大家都知道性感带在哪里
Everyone knows the basic erogenous zones.
有一区  二区  三区
You got one, two, three...
四区
four...
五区  六区  还有七区
five, six and seven.
性感带有七个啊
There are seven?
我看看
Let me see that.
对  没错
Oh, yeah.
那里也算一个
That's one?
还挺重要的呢
Kind of an important one.
反过来看会有误差嘛
Oh, you know, I was looking at it upside down.
有时候反过来也不错
Well, you know, sometimes that helps.
男人大多数爱抚过一区  二区  三区
Okay, now, most guys will hit one, two, three,
就直接跳到第七个区  鸣锣收兵
and then go to seven and set up camp.
那样不好吗
That's bad?
你去迪士尼乐园玩的时候
At Disneyland,
也不会整天只玩马特角雪橇啊
you don't spend the whole day on the Matterhorn.
若像七区这么爽  你可能就会一直玩了
You might if it were like seven.
重点就是  慢慢来
All right, the important thing is to take your time.
七个性感带都要照顾到
You want to hit them all...
还要搭配起来  就像掂脚那样维持紧绷
...mix them up. Keep them on their toes.
脚趾
Oh, toes!
有些人的脚趾会兴奋嘛
For some people.
好吧
All right.
你可以先稍稍爱抚一下一区
You could start out with a little one.
再爱抚二区
A two.
然后一区  二区  三区搭配
A one, two, three.
再来一次三区
A three.
一次五区
A five.
一次四区
A four.
三区和二区一起来
A three, two.
二区  再配个二区  四区和六区
Two. A two, four, six.
再来一遍二  四  六
Two, four, six.
四  二
Four. Two.
二  四和七
Two. Four, seven!
五配七  六配七
Five, seven! Six, seven!
七  七
Seven! Seven!
七  七  七  七  七
Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven!
七
Seven!
盖勒博士  这里有位置
Dr. Geller? There's a seat here.
菲利普斯博士  谢谢你
Thank you, Dr. Phillips.
但我今天要在
But I'm having my lunch...
中间这张桌子前吃午饭
...at this table. Here in the middle.
我就在这张桌子前...
I'm having my lunch...
和我的好友乔伊一起吃午餐
...right here with my good friend, Joey.
若他愿意跟我坐一起的话
If he'll sit with me.
盖勒博士  我跟你坐
I will sit with you, Dr. Geller.
你们知道吗
You know...
我们在自然史博物馆工作
...we work in a museum of natural history.
然而我们吃午饭的方式  却很不自然
And yet, there is something unnatural about the way we eat lunch.
我环顾这餐厅的四周  看到了什么
Now, I look around this cafeteria, and you know what
我看到了隔阂
I see? I see division.
穿白色工作服的人和穿蓝外套的人
Division between people in white coats
彼此间有着深深的隔阂
and people in blue blazers.
我扪心自问  "天啊  这是为什么"
I ask myself, "My God, why?"
我建议大家脱掉
Now, I say we shed these coats...
这些为我们制造隔阂的外套
that separate us.
这样我们才能有机会了解衣冠之下的人心
And we get to know the people underneath.
我是罗斯
I'm Ross!
我离婚了  是一个孩子的父亲
I'm divorced and I have a kid!
我是乔伊  我是个演员
I'm Joey! I'm an actor!
我对恐龙一窍不通
I don't know squat about dinosaurs!
我是泰德  一个月前才搬到这里
I'm Ted, and I just moved here a month ago,
纽约城真是把我吓坏了
and New York really scares me.
-这就对了!  -泰德  你要撑住
- All right! There you go! - You hang in there, Teddy!
我是安德鲁
I'm Andrew.
这颗梨是我偷的
And I didn't pay for this pear.
好  有你的
Okay. Good for you.
我是朗妲  这一对不是真的
I'm Rhonda! And these aren't real!
朗妲
Wow, Rhonda.
-我是史考特  -史考特 加油
- I'm Scott. - Yeah, okay, Scott!
我在离开一个房间之前
And I need to flip the light switch on and off
定要连续开灯关灯17次
17 times before I leave a room...
不然我全家都会死光光
or my family will die.
我妈快来了
My mom's gonna be here any minute.
我不敢面对  我不想送走它
I can't do this. I can't give him up.
不  我能做到
Yes, no. I can.
但我不想
I don't want to.
但是我可以做到
But I can.
不行
No.
我再看下去一定会崩溃
I can't watch this.
简直像《苏菲的选择》那么凄惨
It's like Sophie's Choice.
我从没看过那部电影
You know, I never saw that.
其实很普通而己
Oh, it was only okay.
我办不到
I can't do this.
我妈妈说的对  我连一条狗都舍不得
My mom was right. If I can't give him up...
怎么可能送走自己生的小孩
there's no way I can give up a little baby.
弗兰克和爱丽丝一定会很伤心
Frank and Alice are going to be so crushed.
我能给他点什么别的  肾脏
What else can I give them? A kidney!
我们正好在附近
We were in the neighborhood, so...
我们就是顺路过来跟你说一声
We just stop by and want to let you know
千万不要有压力
that there's still no pressure.
但是如果你有事要跟我们说
But if there was something you wanted to tell us,
我们就坐在那里喝咖啡
we're just gonna be right over there having coffee.
这个小家伙是谁
Who's this little guy?
太可爱了
He's so cute!
让我想起了我以前养过的狗  肿瘤
He reminds me of my old dog, Tumor.
太可人疼了  真想带你回家
You are so precious, I could take you home.
有何不可呢?
Why don't you?
-你没开玩笑吧  -没有啊
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
多谢了
Thanks.
-你在干嘛  -我现在一点也不伤感
- What are you doing? - I'm really okay with this.
知道原因吗  看看他们
You know why? Because look at them.
看看他们满心欢喜的样子
Look how happy they are.
而这是我的功劳  所以...
And I made that, so you know...
我知道送走自己生出来的孩子
It'll be a million times harder
一定会难上百万倍  但是  天呐
to give up a baby, but oh, my God!
到时的快乐定也会是百万倍  对吧
It'll feel a million times better, right?
我决定了  我要怀你们的孩子
I'll do this. I want to carry your baby.
真是太感谢了
Thank you so much!
你简直是我们的大救星
You don't know what this means to us.
天啊  我都快哭了
I think I'm going to cry!
一定会很美好的
It's going to be so great.
-怎么回事  -我把小狗给了他们
- What's going on? - I gave them the puppy.
他们高兴极了  然后我决定做他们的代孕母亲
It made them so happy, that I decided to carry their baby.
-菲比  -你不用说  我知道
- Phoebe... - No, I know.
你我是完全不同的人
You and I are totally different people, though.
而且我们面临的情况也完全不同
And this is a different situation.
我知道我这样做绝不会后梅
And I know that I am not going to regret this.
你说的我都明白
I understand all that.
只不过  那小狗是我的
It's just, that was my puppy.
你愿意帮别人当代孕母亲吗
Would you ever be a surrogate for anyone?
要看是谁要我帮忙
Depends who asked.
如果是我呢?
What if I asked?
莫妮卡  那我当然愿意啊
Oh, Mon, sure!
-真的  -是啊
- Really? - Yes.
你不是真要我帮忙吧
You're not asking me, are you?
-不是  -那我当然帮你  责无旁贷
- No. - Yes. Totally.
谢谢你 谢谢你
Thank you! Thank you!
太感谢你了!
Thank you! Yes, thank you!